<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Project Sport</string>

    <string name="search_title">Search</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_article">Articles</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_calories_counter">Calculators</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_index_body_weight">Body Mass Index</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_day_need_cal">Calorie requirements</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_calc_food">Food Calculator</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_step_counter">Pedometer</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_statistics">My statistics</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_help">Help</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_about_us">About us</string>
    <string name="nav_menu_item_additional_info">Add. information</string>


    <string name="navigation_view_open">Open</string>
    <string name="navigation_view_close">Close</string>

    <string name="preferences_title">Preferences</string>

    <string name="text_your_height">Height:</string>
    <string name="text_your_weight">Weight:</string>
    <string name="text_your_sex">Gender:</string>
    <string name="text_your_sex_M">M</string>
    <string name="text_your_sex_F">F</string>
    <string name="text_your_goal">Target:</string>
    <string name="text_your_time">Time:</string>
    <string name="text_your_age">Age:</string>
    <string name="text_bt_change_your_hw">Change parameters</string>
    <string name="buttonShowListTodayFoodText">List</string>

    <string name="text_ccal">cal</string>

    <string name="tag_fragment_article">ArticleFragment</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_calculate_food">CalculateFoodFragment</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_calculate_details_food">CalculateDetailsFoodFragment</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_index_body">IndexBodyFragment</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_need_calories">NeedCaloriesFragment</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_step_counter">StepCounterFragment</string>

    <string name="temp_text_example_fragment">Articles will be here</string>

    <string name="alertAddFoodTitle">Calculator</string>
    <string name="alertAddFoodMessage">Enter the amount of food:</string>
    <string name="alertAddFoodPositiveBt">Calculate</string>
    <string name="alertAddFoodNegativeBt">Cancel</string>
    <string name="toastMistake">Enter the amount of selected food!</string>
    <string name="alertAddFoodEditTextHintText">100</string>
    <string name="alertChangeTodayList">Today:</string>


    <string name="alertChangeTodayListCategoryFood">Category:</string>
    <string name="alertChangeTodayListNameFood">Title:</string>
    <string name="alertChangeTodayListDeleteTitle">Delete entry</string>
    <string name="alertChangeTodayListDeleteMessage">Delete entry?</string>
    <string name="alertChangeTodayListDeleteButtonText">Delete</string>
    <string name="alertChangeUserInfoTitle">Your physical parameters</string>
    <string name="alertChangeUserInfoMessage">
        Enter new values ​​for gender, age, height and weight: \n \nAge from 16 years, height from 75 cm, weight from 25 kg
   </string>
    <string name="alertChangeUserInfoButtonPositive">Confirm</string>
    <string name="alertChangeUserInfoButtonNegative">Cancel</string>

    <string name="hint_weight">Weight in kilograms</string>
    <string name="hint_height">Height in centimeters</string>
    <string name="hint_age">Age</string>
    <string name="hint_food_weight">Weight in grams</string>
    <string name="hint_target_step_count">Number of steps</string>

    <string name="title_activity_activity_other_calculators">Fitness Calculator</string>

    <string name="text_normal_index_body_min">Minimum</string>
    <string name="text_normal_index_body_ideal">Ideal</string>
    <string name="text_normal_index_body_max">Maximum</string>
    <string name="text_normal_index_body_normal">Body Mass Index</string>
    <string name="text_bt_calculate_index">Calculate index</string>
    <string name="text_normal_index_body_min_value">18</string>
    <string name="text_normal_index_body_ideal_value">22</string>
    <string name="text_normal_index_body_max_value">25</string>

    <string name="alertIndexBodyTitle">Body Mass Index</string>
    <string name="alertIndexBodyPositiveBt">Calculate</string>
    <string name="alertIndexBodyNegativeBt">Cancel</string>
    <string name="alertIndexBodyMessage">Enter height and weight: \n \nHeight from 75 cm, weight from 25 kg</string>
    <string name="text_user_info_from_DB">Use parameters from settings</string>
    <string name="text_user_info_new_input_info">Enter new data</string>
    <string name="text_err_input_index_body">Enter height and weight!</string>
    <string name="text_zero">0</string>
    <string name="text_your_index_body">Your body mass index is:</string>


    <string name="text_index_body_less_min">
        Your body mass index is less than normal. Perhaps you should reconsider your diet,
        to put on some weight.
   </string>
    <string name="text_index_body_min">
        Your body mass index is at the low end of the normal range. Perhaps if you dial a few more
        kilogram, you will feel a little better and get closer to your ideal weight.
   </string>
    <string name="text_index_body_ideal">
        Your body mass index is nearly perfect. Continue in the same spirit! Healthy lifestyle -
        this is really the right choice!
   </string>
    <string name="text_index_body_max">
        Your body mass index is at the high end of the normal range. Maybe you need a little
        change your diet and you will get closer to your ideal weight.
   </string>
    <string name="text_index_body_excess">
        Your body mass index is indicative of being overweight. Maybe you need a little
        change your diet and you will return to your normal weight.
   </string>
    <string name="text_index_body_obesity_1">
        Your body mass index is indicative of the first stage of obesity. You should reconsider
        your diet and perhaps exercise or fitness. Going to the gym will go
        Benefit and help you lose weight.
   </string>
    <string name="text_index_body_obesity_2">
        Your body mass index is indicative of a second stage of obesity. You should reconsider
        your diet and be sure to go in for sports or fitness. Going to the gym will go
        Benefit and help you lose weight.
   </string>
    <string name="text_index_body_obesity_3">
        Your body mass index is at the third stage of obesity. You should urgently
        revise your diet and be sure to go in for sports or fitness. Going to the gym will go
        Benefit and help you lose weight.
   </string>

    <string name="text_need_calories">Your Daily Calories:</string>
    <string name="text_bt_calculate_need_calories">Calculate rate</string>
    <string name="text_need_calories_title">Calories Rate</string>
    <string name="text_need_calories_normal">Without changing the weight:</string>
    <string name="text_need_calories_loss_weight">Slimming:</string>
    <string name="text_need_calories_fast_loss_weight">Fast weight loss:</string>

    <string name="text_spinner_life_style_title">Exercise level</string>

    <string name="alertChoiceUserInfoMessage">
        Enter the values ​​for gender, height and weight: \n \nAge from 16 years old, height from 75 cm, weight from 25 kg</string>
    <string name="text_err_input_user_info_need_calories">Enter your age, height and weight!</string>
    <string name="text_need_calories_spinner_title">Choose your lifestyle:</string>


    <string name="text_step_counter">Passed</string>
    <string name="text_step_counter_steps">steps</string>
    <string name="text_step_counter_from">from</string>
    <string name="text_bt_step_counter_start">Start</string>
    <string name="text_bt_step_counter_stop">Stop</string>
    <string name="text_bt_step_counter_reset">Reset</string>
    <string name="text_bt_step_counter_target">Select target</string>
    <string name="text_percent">%</string>
    <string name="alertTargetStepCountTitle">Your target:</string>
    <string name="alertTargetStepCountMessage">Enter the number of steps you want to take daily. \n \n (From 100 steps)</string>
    <string name="alertTargetStepCountPositiveBt">Confirm</string>
    <string name="alertTargetStepCountNegativeBt">Cancel</string>
    <string name="toast_err_target_step_count">Enter the number of steps</string>
    <string name="hint_start_step_counter">Press \"Start \" to turn on the pedometer</string>
    <string name="alertResetTitle">Reset pedometer</string>
    <string name="alertResetMessage">Are you sure you want to reset the pedometer value?</string>
    <string name="alertResetPositiveBt">Yes</string>
    <string name="alertResetNegativeBt">Cancel</string>
    <string name="toastMistakeUserInfo">Enter weight, height and age parameters!</string>


    <string name="tab_sport_article">Sports</string>
    <string name="tab_food_article">Food</string>
    <string name="tab_fitness_article">Fitness</string>
    <string name="text_your_statistics">Statistics</string>

    <string name="tab_statistics_week">Week</string>
    <string name="tab_statistics_month">Month</string>
    <string name="text_days">Days</string>
    <string name="text_your_normal_ccal">Normal</string>
    <string name="title_articles">Articles</string>
    <string name="title_statistics">My statistics</string>
    <string name="toastMistakeMinValuesUserInfo">Enter values for age, weight and height greater than the specified minimum values ​​</string>
    <string name="toastMistakeMinValuesUserPrefInfo">The entered values for age, weight and height are greater than the specified minimum values! No data will be applied!</string>
    <string name="toastMistakeZero">Enter the amount of selected food greater than 0!</string>
    <string name="toastMistakeMinValuesIndexBody">Enter weight and height values ​​greater than the specified minimum values!</string>
    <string name="toast_mistake_min_target_step_count">Please enter the minimum valid target value!</string>

    <string name="help_activity_title">Help</string>
    <string name="help_text_calculators">
    There are 3 types of fitness calculators in this application: Food calculator and BMI calculators and
    calorie needs. \n \n
    The food calculator allows you to count the number of calories you consumed with food.
    To count calories with it, you need to select the Type of food consumed from the list, and
    then the food itself, and then enter the amount of food consumed in the dialog box. \n
    In the upper left of the screen, you can view the list of food consumed today by clicking
    by clicking the \"List \" button, and also change your values ​​for height, weight, gender and age, based on which
    the calculator calculates your minimum daily calorie requirement by clicking on the button
    \"Change settings \". \n \n
</string>
    <string name="help_text_step_counter">
    In this application, you can count the steps taken using a pedometer. \n \n
    To start the pedometer press the \"Start \" button in the pedometer window. Accordingly, to stop and
    To reset the current pedometer value, press the \"Stop \", \"Reset \" buttons. \n \n
</string>
    <string name="help_text_articles">
    By selecting the menu item \"Articles \", you can find very useful information about sports, nutrition and fitness,
    which will help you lead a healthy life. \n \n
</string>
    <string name="help_text_statistics">
    By going to the menu item \"My statistics \", you can visually view the statistics of consumed
    You the food that you counted with the "Food Calculator". \n \n
</string>
    <string name="help_text_settings">
    To go to the application settings, go to the \"Settings \" menu item. \n \n In this item you
    can choose a color theme for the entire application, and also enter or change your
    parameters of gender, age, height and weight, which are used in various calculations in
    this application. \n \n
</string>
    <string name="title_activity_scrolling">ScrollingActivity</string>
    <string name="large_text">
    "Material is the metaphor. \n \n"

    "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
    "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet"
    "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic. \n"
    "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The"
    "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the"
    "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical"
    "world, without breaking the rules of physics. \n"
    "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move,"
    "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows"
    "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts. \n \n"

    "Bold, graphic, intentional. \n \n"

    "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color,"
    "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the"
    "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge"
    "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic"
    "interface that immerse the user in the experience. \n"
    "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides"
    "waypoints for the user. \n \n"

    "Motion provides meaning. \n \n"

    "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are"
    "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design. \n"
    "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without"
    "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize. \n"
    "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity."
    "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are ef ﬁ cient yet coherent. \n \n"

    "3D world. \n \n"

    "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z"
    "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the"
    "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single"
    "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness. \n"
    "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is"
    "emulated by manipulating the y-axis. \n \n"

    "Light and shadow. \n \n"

    "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create"
    "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles. \n"
    "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android"
    "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at"
    "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the"
    "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp. \n \n"

    "Resting elevation. \n \n"

    "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation"
    "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting"
    "elevation as soon as possible. \n \n"

    "Component elevations. \n \n"

    "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation"
    "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app). \n"
    "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth"
    "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop). \n \n"

    "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets. \n \n"

    "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response"
    "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation"
    "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets. \n"
    "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative"
    "to the component's resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent"
    "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have"
    "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation. \n"
    "Once the input event is completed or canceled, the component will return to its resting"
    "elevation. \n \n"

    "Avoiding elevation interference. \n \n"

    "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between"
    "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass"
    "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways,"
    "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout. \n"
    "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference."
    "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a"
    "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears. \n"
    "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference."
    "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere"
    "when a user tries to pick up one of cards. \n \n"
</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="tab_help_description">Description</string>
    <string name="tab_help_procedure">Actions</string>

    <string name="help_text_calculators_proc">
    There are 3 fitness calculators in the app: \n \n

    1) Body Mass Index Calculator; \n
    2) Calorie requirement calculator; \n
    3) Food calculator; \n \n

              Body Mass Index Calculator: \n \n

    To calculate the body mass index, select the menu item \"Body mass index \" \n
    ->Press the button \"Calculate index \" \n
    ->In the dialog box, enter your height in centimeters and weight in kilograms, \n
       after selecting the item \"Enter new data \"; you can also select the item \n
       \"Use parameters from settings \" so as not to enter your height and weight, but \n
       calculate body mass index based on your saved in the application \n
       height and weight data \n
    ->Press the \"Calculate \" button \n
    ->Your body mass index will appear on the screen \n \n

              Calorie Needs Calculator: \n \n

    To calculate your need for calories, select the menu item \"Need for calories \" \n
    ->In the dropdown list, select your lifestyle \n
    ->Press the button \"Calculate rate \" \n
    ->In the dialog box, enter your height in centimeters and weight in kilograms, as well as, \n
       gender and age by selecting the item \"Enter new data \"; you can also \n
       select the item \"Use parameters from settings \" in order not to enter your height, weight, \n
       age and gender, and calculate the body mass index based on your saved in the application \n
       data on height, weight, gender and age \n
    ->Press the \"Confirm \" button \n
    ->The screen will show your daily calorie intake without changing the weight, as well as the rate for \n
       normal and fast weight loss \n \n

              Food Calculator: \n \n

    To calculate the calorie content of consumed food, select the menu item \"Food calculator \" \n
    ->Select the type of food consumed (fruits, vegetables, etc.) from the list \n
    ->Select the food you want from the list that appears \n
    ->In the dialog box, enter the weight of the food in grams \n
    ->Press the \"Calculate \" button \n
    ->The selected food will be added to the list of food consumed by you for the day \n \n

    To view the food consumed for the current day, click on the \"List \" button in \n
    top corner of the screen \n
    ->In the dialog box, you can see the food consumed per day, as well as information about it \n \n

    At the top of the screen, you can see your height, weight, gender and age data, which \n
    are used to calculate your minimum calorie intake (which is in the right \n
    top corner of the screen). You can change them by clicking on the \"Change settings \" button and \n
    enter new data in the dialog box. \n \n

    The statistics of the food you have counted in the \"Food Calculator \" you can \n
    look in the menu item \"My statistics \". \n \n
</string>
    <string name="help_text_step_counter_proc">
    To open the pedometer, select the \"Pedometer \" menu item. \n \n

    You can do the following with the pedometer: \n
    ->Press the \"Start \" button to start the pedometer \n
    ->Press the \"Stop \" button to stop the pedometer \n
    ->Press the \"Reset \" button to reset the current \n
       pedometer values ​​\n
    ->Press the button \"Select target \", and in the appeared \n
       dialog box select the number of steps, \n
       which you want to pass (from this amount) \n
       percentages will be calculated (degree of achievement \n
       target), and then click the \"Confirm \" button \n \n
</string>
    <string name="help_text_articles_proc">
    For helpful articles on sports, nutrition, and fitness, \n
    select the menu item \"Articles \" \n
    ->Then select the required article from the list \n \n
</string>
    <string name="help_text_statistics_proc">
    To see the statistics calculated in the \"Food calculator \" \n
    food, select the menu item \"My statistics \". \n \n

    At the top of the screen, select the tab \"Week \" and \"Month \", \n
    to view statistics for the week and month respectively. \n \n
</string>
    <string name="help_text_settings_proc">
    To change some of the settings for your application, select \n
    menu item \"Settings \". \n \n

    There are 2 categories of settings in the application: \n \n

    1) General application settings \n
    2) Personal user settings \n \n

              General Application Settings: \n \n

    By selecting this item of settings, you can change the color \n
    application theme. \n \n

              User personal settings: \n \n

    By selecting this item of settings, you can set such \n
    data like your height, west, gender, age and name. \n \n
</string>
</resources>